# Panagiotis Simakis

Curriculum Vitae

Athens, 115 27, Greece

#### Summary

Software Engineer with more than 5 years of working experience in the field of Software Development, Data Science, Data Engineering & MLOps. Has worked in various sectors from Digital Marketing to e-Commerce. Loves to work with Modern Data Stacks and to productize Machine Learning Systems. He usually contributes to FOSS projects during the nights.

### EXPERIENCE

#### Netdata

Senior Data Engineer

Oct. 2021 - Present

Development of ETL pipelines.

Technologies: Airflow, BigQuery, GCP, Docker

Convert Group

Athens, Greece

Data Engineer

May 2020 - Sep. 2021

Development of ETL pipelines and data automation pipelines. Productize the inernal Machine Learning services. Contribute on back-end development of eRetail Content platform.

**Technologies:** Prefect, AWS, Django/REST, Docker, PostgreSQL, Amazon Redshift, Celery

XPLAIN

Athens, Greece

Data Scientist

Feb. 2017 - Apr. 2020

Data and Text Mining using state-of-the-art and disruptive methods. Design and development of distributed web crawlers. Database administration and optimization. Implementation of workflow pipelines. Deployment of ML models to production as RESTfull API services.

Technologies: Python, MySQL, Celery, Docker Swarm, ELK, spaCy, NumPy/pandas

Sociality

Athens, Greece

Junior Web Developer - Intern

Feb. 2016 - June 2016

Web development using WordPress. Implementation of WordPress plugins for Woocommerce. Development of custom functionalities for WordPress.

**Technologies:** WordPress, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming & Markup Languages: Python, Shell, SQL, PHP
- Databases & Big Data: MySQL, Redis, PostgreSQL, Elastic Stack
- Data & ML Workflow Platforms: Prefect, MLflow, Apache Airflow
- Data Science & NLP: pandas/NumPy, scikit-learn, Keras, spaCy
- Web Scraping: lxml, Selenium, Scrapy, Beautiful Soup
- Web Frameworks: Django/REST, FastAPI
- Version Control Systems & Platforms: Git, Github, Bitbucket

### **EDUCATION**

### Department of Computer Engineering & Informatics, University of Patras

Patras, Greece

Diploma (equivalent to B.Eng + M.Eng); GPA: 6.87

Sep. 2010 - Feb. 2017

**Thesis**: Design and Implementation of a Methodology for the Automatic Identification of the User Geographic Idiom in a Social Media Text Corpus. supervisor: Megalooikonomou Vasileios, grade: 10/10

### LANGUAGES

• Greek: Native

• English: Proficient

Certificate of Proficiency in English, The University of Mishigan

• French: Elementary Delf A2

## CERTIFICATIONS & CONFERENCES

• Architecting with Google Kubernetes Engine Specialization: Coursera 🚱	Dec. 2021
• AWS Fundamentals Specialization: Coursera &	Nov. 2020
• O $\pi$ e\n conference: Athens, Greece $\mathscr{G}$	Mar. 2019
• Spark and Python for Big Data with PySpark: Udemy &	Dec. 2017
• 4th & 10th Conference of FOSS: Patras, Athens, Greece the full list	2011, 2017

# PUBLICATIONS

- Simaki, V., Simakis, P., Paradis, C., & Kerren, A. (2018). Detection of StanceRelated Characteristics in Social Media Text. In SETN '18: 10th Hellenic Conference on Artificial Intelligence New York: Association for Computing Machinery, Inc. DOI: 10.1145/3200947.3201017
- Simaki, V., Simakis, P., Paradis, C, & Kerren, A. (2017). Identifying the Authors' National Variety of English in Social Media Text. In Proceedings of RANLP 2017 Recent Advances in Natural Language, ACL Anthology (in press)

### Interests

GNU/Linux, MLOps, NLP, F/OSS

### ACTIVITIES

Photography, Traveling, Hiking, Sailing